Guide to the Yale Divinity School Faculty Writings and Publications
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Faculty A-L
  - Childs, Brevard S.
    - The Enemy from the North and the Chaos Tradition. Journal of Biblical Literature, LXXVIII/III (1959) pp. 187-188. (Box 4)
    - The Etiological Tale Re-Examined., n.d. (Box 4)
    - The Exegetical Significance of Canon for the Study of the Old Testament, Congress Volume (1977), pp. 66-80. (Box 4)
    - Introduction to the Old Testament as Scripture, Response to Reviewers of Journal for the Study of the Old Testament, n.d. (Box 4)
    - Jonah: A Study in Old Testament Hermeneutics. Scottish Journal of Theology, II/1 (Feb 1958) pp. 52-61. (Box 4)
    - The Old Testament as Scripture of the Church. Concordia Theological Monthly, v.43 (1972) pp. 709-722. (Box 4)
    - On Reading the Elijah Narratives. Interpretation, XXXIV/2 (Apr 1980) pp. 127-137. (Box 4)
    - Psalm Titles and Midrashic Exegesis. Journal of Semitic Studies, 16/2 (Autumn 1971) pp. 137-150. (Box 4)
    - Psalm 8 in the Context of the Christian Canon, n.d. (Box 4)
    - The Search for Biblical Authority Today. Andover Newton Quarterly 16/3 (Jan 1976) pp. 199-206. (Box 4)
    - The Sensus Literalis of Scripture: An Ancient and Modern Problem. Beitrage Zur Alttestamentlichen Theologie. pp. 80-93. (Box 4)
    - Some Reflections on the Search for a Biblical Theology. Horizons in Biblical Theology, 4/1 (Jan 1982) pp. 1-12. (Box 4)
    - A Study of the Formula "Until this Day". Journal of Biblical Literature LXXVIII/III (1959) pp. 187-188. (Box 4)
    - A Traditio-Historical Study of the Reed Sea Tradition. Vetus Testamentum XX/4 (1970) pp. 406-418. (Box 4)
    - Wellhausen in English (abstract), n.d. (Box 4)
  - Christian, William A.
    - The Creation of the World. Special Aspects of St. Augustine's Thought, pp.315-342., n.d. (Box 4)
    - A Definition of Religion. The Review of Religion, May 1941, p. 412-429. (Box 4)
    - The Dilemma of the Liberal, pp. 1-22., n.d. (Box 4)
    - In Memory of Robert L. Calhoun, 1896-1983. Reflection, Nov 1984, p. 16. (Box 4)
    - Not for quotation. (A section of a paper) no title, n.d., pp. 41-87. (Box 4)
  - Collins, Adela Yarbro
    - Apocalypse and Politics. Printed in The Looking Glass: Essays in Celebration of a Precursor for Robert W. Funk, Forum 8, 1992, pp. 297-312. (Box 65)
    - The Apocalyptic Ekphrasis. Printed in the Holy Monastery of Saint John the Theologian in Patmos, ed., 1900th Anniversary of Saint John's Apocalypse: Proceedings of the International and Interdisciplinary Symposium (Athens—Patmos, 17-26 September 1995) (Athens: Holy Monastery of Saint John the Theologian in Patmos), 1999, pp. 449-464. (Box 65)
    - The Apocalyptic Rhetoric of Mark 13 in Historical Context. Printed in Biblical Research 41, 1996, pp. 5-36. (Box 65)
    - The Apocalyptic Son of Man Sayings. Printed in The Future of Early Christianity: Essays in Honor of Helmut Koester. Edited by B.A. Pearson, A. T. Kraabel, G. Nickelsburg and N. Petersen. Minneapolis: Fortress Press, 1991, pp. 220-228. (Box 65)
    - Apocalyptic Themes in Biblical Literature. Printed in Interpretation 53, 1999, pp.117-130. (Box 65)
    - The Appropriation of the Psalms of Individual Lament by Mark. C. M. Tuckett, ed. Printed in The Scriptures in the Gospels, BETL 131, Leuven: Leuven University Press/ Uitgeverij Peeters, 1997, pp. 223-241. (Box 65)
    - Composition and Redaction of the Testament of Moses 10. Printed in Harvard Theological Review 69, 1976, pp. 179-186. (Box 65)
    - The Composition of the Passion Narrative in Mark. Printed in Sewanee Theological Review 36, 1992, pp. 57-77. (Box 4)
    - Crisis and Community in John's Gospel. Printed in Theology Digest 27:4, 1979, pp. 313-321. (Box 65)
    - Daniel 7 and the Historical Jesus. Printed in Of Scribes and Scrolls, Studies on the Hebrew Bible, Intertesamental Judaism and Christian Origins, presented to John Strugnell on the occasion of his sixtieth birthday. College Theology Society Resources in Religion, 5, 1990, pp. 187-193. (Box 65)
    - Early Christian Apocalyptic Literature. Printed in Aufstieg und Hiedergang der romischen Welt (ANRW), Rise and Decline of the Roman World, ed. by Wolfgang Haase and Hildegard Temporini, Part II: v.25.6, 1988, pp. 4665-4711. (Box 65)
    - The Eschatological Discourse of Mark 13. Printed in The Four Gospels 1992: Festschrift Frans Neirynck. Edited by F. Van Segbroeck, C. M. Tuckett, G. Van Belle, and J. Verheyden. BETL 100, Gembloux:Leuven University Press/Peeters, 1992. Vol. 2, pp. 1125-1140. (Box 65)
    - Eschatology in the Book of Revelation. Printed in Ex Auditu, v.6, 1990, pp. 63-72. (Box 65)
    - Establishing the Text: Mark 1:1. Printed in Texts and Contexts: Biblical Texts in Their Textual and Contexts: Situational Essays in Honor of Lars Hartman. Ed. Tord Fornberg and David Hellholm, Oslo: Scandinavian University Press, 1995, pp. 111-127. (Box 65)
    - Feminine Symbolism in the Book of Revelation. Printed in Biblical Interpretation 1, 1993, pp. 20-33. (Box 65)
    - Feminist Perspectives on Biblical Scholarship. Printed in Biblical Scholarship in North America; Society of Biblical Literature Centennial Publications, Scholars Press, 1985, pp. 1-9., 1995 (Box 65)
    - Finding Meaning in the Death of Jesus. Printed in Journal of Religion, 78, 1998, pp.175-196. (Box 65)
    - From Noble Death to Crucified Messiah. Printed in New Testament Studies 40, 1994, pp. 481-503. (Box 65)
    - The Function of "Excommunication" in Paul. Printed in Harvard Theological Review 73, 1980, pp. 251-263. (Box 65)
    - Gegner von tauben: rom als Prototyp des Bösen im frühen Christentum. Printed in Concilium 200, 1988, pp. 473-480. (Box 65)
    - Genre and the Gospels. A Review Article on Richard A. Burridge, What Are the Gospels? A Comparison with Graeco-Roman Biography. Printed in The Journal of Religion 75, 1995, pp. 239-246. (Box 65)
    - The Genre of the Passion Narrative. Printed in Studia Theologica 47, 1993, pp. 3-28. (Box 65)
    - The Gospel and Women. The 1987 Fred O. Francis Memorial Lectures in Religion, Chapman College, 1987. (Box 65)
    - The History-of-Religions Approach to Apocalypticism and the 'Angel of the Waters' (Rev 16;4-7). Printed in Catholic Biblical Quarterly 39, 1977, pp. 367-381 (Box 65)
    - An Inclusive Biblical Anthropology. Printed in Theology Today, January, 1978, v. 34, no. 4, pp. 358-369. (Box 65)
    - Insiders and Outsiders in the Book of Revelation and Its Social Context. Printed in To See Ourselves As Others See Us: Jews, Christians, "Others" in Late Antiquity, ed. Jacob Neusner and Ernest S. Frerichs. Studies in the Humanities. Atlanta: Scholars Press, 1985, pp. 187-218. (Box 65)
    - Introduction: Early Christian Apocalypticism. Printed in Semeia 36, 1986, pp. 1-11 (Box 65)
    - Jesus' Action in Herod's Temple. Printed in Antiquity and Humanity: Essays on Ancient Religion and Philosophy, presented to Hans Dieter Betz on his 70 th birthday, Mohr Siebeck, 2001, pp. 45-61. (Box 65)
    - Jesus and the Jerusalem Temple. Printed in International Rennert Guest Lecture Series 5, 1999,pp. 1-14. (Box 65)
    - Mark and His Readers: The Son of God among Jews. Printed in Harvard Theological Review 92, 1999, pp. 393-408 (Box 65)
    - Mark and His Readers: The Son of God among Greeks and Romans. Printed in Harvard Theological Review, 93 no 2 Ap 2000, p 85-100. (Box 65)
    - Meaning and Significance in Apocalyptic Texts. Printed inTextual Fidelity and Textual Disregard,American University Studies III. 33. Ed. Bernard Dauenhauer. New York: Peter Lang, 1990, pp. 105-119., 1999 (Box 65)
    - Messianic Secret and the Gospel of Mark: Secrecy in Jewish Apocalypticism, the Hellenistic Mystery Religions, and Magic. Printed in Rending the Veil: Concealment and Secrecy in the History of Religions, New York University Annual Conference in Comparative Religions, Elliot R. Wolfson, ed., New York University, Seven Bridges Press, 1999, pp. 11-30. (Box 65)
    - Mysteries in the Gospel of Mark. Printed in Mighty Minorities? Minorities in Early Christianity--Positions and Strategies. Essays in Honor of Jacob Jervell, ed. David Hellholm, Halvor Moxnes and Turid Karlsen Seim. Studia Theologica: Scandinavian Journal of Theology 49, 1995, pp. 11-23 (Box 65)
    - Myth and History in the Book of Revelation: The Problem of Its Date. Printed in Traditions in Transformation: Turning Points in Biblical Faith. Essays in honor of Frank Moore Cross, Jr.; ed. Baruch Halpern and Jon Levenson; Winona Lake: Eisenbrauns, 1981, pp. 377-403. (Box 65)
    - Narrative, History, and Gospel. Printed in Genre, Narrativity and Theology, ed. Mary Gerhart and James Williams. Semeia 43, 1988, pp. 145-153. (Box 65)
    - New Testament Perspectives: The Gospel of John. Printed in The Effects of Women's Studies on Biblical Studies, Journal for the Study of the Old Testament, v.22, 1982, pp. 47-53. (Box 65)
    - Numerical Symbolism in Jewish and Early Christian Apocalyptic Literature. Printed in Aufstieg und Niedergang der römischen Welt, II.21.2; ed. Wolfgang Haase; Berlin and New York: de Gruyter,1984, pp. 1223-1287. (Box 65)
    - Oppression from Without: The Symbolisation of Rome as Evil in Early Christianity. Printed in Concilium 200, 1988, pp. 66-74. (Box 65)
    - The Origin of Christian Baptism. Printed in Studia Liturgica 19, 1989, pp. 28-46. (Box 65)
    - The Origin of the Designation of Jesus as "Son of Man". Printed in HTR 80:4, 1987, pp. 391-407. (Box 65)
    - Pergamon in Early Christian Literature. Printed in Pergamon, Citadel of the Gods, Archaeological Record, Literary Description and Religious Development, Harvard Theological Studies 46, Chapter 7, pp. 163-184., 1998 (Box 65)
    - Persecution and Vengeance in the Book of Revelation. Printed in Apocalypticism in the Mediterranean World and the Near East. Proceedings of the International Colloquium on Apocalypticism, Uppsala, August 12-17, 1979, J. C. B. Mohr (Paul Siebeck), 1983, pp. 729-749. (Box 65)
    - Political Perspective of the Revelation to John. Printed in JBL 96/2, 1977, pp. 241-256. (Box 65)
    - Reading the Book of Revelation in the Twentieth Century. Printed in Interpretation, July 1986, pp. 229-242. (Box 65)
    - Recent Interpretations of Jesus. Printed in Pacific Theological Review, Reflections for Ministry Today, v. 18, no.2, 1985, pp. 31-42. (Box 65)
    - Response to Luke Timothy Johnson's The Real Jesus. Printed in The Bulletin for Biblical Research 7, 1997, pp. 227-232. (Box 65)
    - Revelation 18: Taunt-Song or Dirge? Printed in l'Apocalypse johannique et l'apocalyptique dans le Nouveau Testament, the Congress Volume of the Biblical Colloquium at Louvain (August, 1979); ed. Jan Lambrecht; Gembloux: Duculot and Leuven University Press, 1980, pp. 185-204. (Box 65)
    - Rulers, Divine Men, and Walking on the Water (Mark6:45-52). Printed in Religious Propaganda and Missionary Competition in the New Testament World: Essays Honoring Dieter Georgi. Supplements to Novum Testamentum 74. Ed. Lukas Bormann, Kelly Del Tredici, and Angela Standhartinger, 1994, pp. 207-227. (Box 65)
    - The Seven Heavens in Jewish and Christian Apocalypses. Printed in Death, Ecstasy, and Other Worldly Journeys. Ed. by John J. Collins and Michael Fishbane. Series in Judaica: Hermeneutics, Mysticism, and Culture. Albany: State University of New York Press, 1995, Chapter 4, pp. 59-93. (Box 65)
    - The Signification of Mark 10:45 among Gentile Christians. Printed in Harvard Theological Review, 90:4, 1997, pp. 371-382. (Box 65)
    - The Son of Man Sayings in the Sayings Source. Printed in To Touch the Text: Biblical and Related Studies in Honor of Joseph A. Fitzmyer, ed. Maurya P. Horgan and Paul J. Kobelski. New York: Crossroad, 1989, pp. 369-389. (Box 65)
    - The "Son of Man" Tradition and the Book of Revelation. Printed in The Messiah: Developments in Earliest Judaism and Christianity, ed. James H. Charlesworth. Minneapolis: Fortress, 1992, pp. 536-568. (Box 65)
    - "Remove This Cup": Suffering and Healing in the Gospel of Mark. Printed in Suffering and Healing in Our Day. Proceedings of the Theology Institute of Villanova University 22. Ed. Francis A. Eigo. Villanova, PA: Villanova University Press, 1990, pp. 29-61. (Box 65)
    - Vilification and Self-Definition in the Book of Revelation. Printed in Harvard Theological Review 79:1-3, 1986, pp. 308-320. (Box 65)
    - "What the Spirit Says to the Churches": Preaching the Apocalypse. Printed in Quarterly Review, v. 4, no. 3, 1984, pp. 69-84. (Box 65)
    - Women's History and the Book of Revelation. Printed in Society of Biblical Literature 1987 Seminar Papers, ed. Kent H. Richards, Atlanta: Scholars Press, 1987, pp. 80-91. (Box 65)
  - Cook, John W.
    - Art and Religion in El Greco's Spain, pp.1-20. (Box 4)
    - Building Divinity: The Sterling Divinity Quadrangle at Yale Divinity School, Institute of Sacred Music, 1994, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Christianity and the Visual Arts. Foward to issue REflection, Vol. 79, No. 1, Nov 1981, p.5. (Box 4)
    - A Conversation with Philip JOhnson. Architecture Plus, Sept. 1973, pp. 62-80. (Box 4)
    - Images of Creation. Creation: The Arena of the Divine Drama. Reflection, 1979, pp. 6-13. (Box 4)
    - Images of Jonah. Reflection, Vol. 76, No. 1, Nov 1978, pp. 9-11. (Box 4)
    - A New Chronology of Hanns von Burhausen's Late Gothic Architecture. Gesta, Journal of International Center of Medieval Art, Vol XV, No. 1 and 2, Summer 1976, pp. 97-104. (Box 4)
    - Picturing Theology: Martin Luther and LUcas Cranach, pp. 6-13. (Box 4)
    - Review of Medieval Structure: The Gothic Vault by James H. Aeland. Architectura, Munich, 1973, pp. 174-176. (Box 4)
    - Sources for the Study of Christianity and the Arts. Art, Creativity, and the Sacred, ed. Diane Aposlotos-Cappadona, pp. 321-329. (Box 4)
    - Spiritual Attitudes in Abstract Expressionism. Religion and Intellectual Life, Vol. 1, No. 1, Fall 1983, pp. 19-32 (Box 4)
    - Spirituality in Stone. Reflection, Vol. 75, No. 1, Nov 1977, pp. 10-13. (Box 4)
    - Structures and Meaning: Values Apparent in Architectural Design. Soundings, Vol. LVII, No. 3, Fall 1974, pp. 305-317. (Box 4)
    - Temples of Culture. Reflection, Jan 1974, pp. 1-4. (Box 4)
    - Thank God for Cellos. Journal of the National Association of Schools of Music, 1976, pp. 43-48. (Box 4)
    - Theology and the Arts: Sources and Resources. Theology Today, Vol. 34, No. 1, Apr 1977, pp. 45-51. (Box 4)
    - A Theology of Light in Architecture. pp.1-22., n.d. (Box 4)
    - Ugly Is Beautiful: The Main Street School of Architecture. Atlantic Monthly, May 1973, pp. 33-43. (Box 4)
  - Copeland, M. Shawn
    - Report to the Lilly Endowment on the Working Conference on Partners in the Conversation: the role of ecumenical divinity schools in Catholic theological education, 23 pages. (Box 4)
  - Cully, Iris V.
    - Problems of Bible Instruction in American Catechetical Literature. Concilium, 1970, pp. 128-139. (Box 4)
  - Dahl, George
    - Articles, offprints
      - The Book of Psalms. Pilgrim Series: Primary Teacher's Guide, Oct-Dec 1950, p. 6- (Box 5)
      - The Case for the Currently Accepted Date of Deuteronomy. Journal of Biblical Literature: 1928, pp. 358-379. (Box 5)
      - Crisis in Ezekiel Research. Quantulacumque: 1937, pp. 265- 284. (Box 5)
      - The Materials for the History of Dor. Transactions of the Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences: May, 1915, pp. 7-131. (Box 5)
      - The Messianic Expectation in the Psalter. Journal of Biblical Literature: 1938, pp. 1-12. (Box 5)
      - Methods of Teaching the Old Testament. Christian Education: Nov, 1930, pp. 110-124. (Box 5)
      - The Problem of the Ephod. Anglican Theological Review: Oct, 1952, pp. 206-210. (Box 5)
      - Revision of the American Standard Version. Journal of Bible and Religion: May, 1941, pp. 104-106. (Box 5)
      - Shall Prospective Ministerial Students Study Bible While in College? Christian Education: Oct., 1931, pp. 38-45. (Box 5)
      - Some Recent Interpretations of Second Isaiah. Journal of Biblical Literature: 1929, pp. 362-379. (Box 5)
      - The "Three Heights" of Joshua 17ii. Journal of Biblical Literature: 1934, pp. 381-383. (Box 5)
      - Various outlines for Old Testament Lectures. (Box 5)
    - Book Reviews
      - Roach, Corwin C. Preaching Values in the Bible, n.d. (Box 5)
      - Notes: Liber Chronicorum by S. Baer---Dahl's marginal notes, 1888., n.d. (Box 5)
  - Dahl, Nils Alstrup
    See Record Group No. 30.
  - Davenport, John Gaylord
    - Moses Stuart - The Man Who Unfettered Religious Thought in America. The Connecticut Magazine, 1907, pp. 111-124. (Box 7)
  - Dirks, John Edward
    - Freedom and Responsibility in the Contemporary University World: Essays in Academic and Theological Dialogue. (Manuscript) 1960. (Box 7)
    - The Impact of Religious Pluralism in the University. Boston University Graduate Journal, Apr 1962, pp. 112-122. (Box 7)
    - The University was Made for Men. Queen's Quarterly, v. LXIX, No. 1, pp. 69-82., n.d. (Box 7)
  - Dittes, James E.
    See Record Group No. 174.
  - Duncombe, David C.
    - Five Years at Yale: The Seminar on the Chronically Ill. Jour. of Pastoral Care, Sep. 1974, pp. 152-163. (Box 7)
  - Dwight, Timothy
    - Inaugural Address. 1886, pp. 17-45. (Box 7)
    - Memorial Address--Theodore Dwight Woolsey. 1890, pp. 3- 29. (Box 7)
  - Farley, Margaret A.
    - An Ethic for Same-Sex Relations. A Challenge to Love, 1983, pp.93-106. (Box 8)
    - New Patterns of Relationship: Beginnings of a Moral Revolution. Woman:New Dimensions, pp.51-70., n.d. (Box 8)
    - Review of Donagan's The Theory Morality. Religious Studies Review, January 1981, pp. 233-237. (Box 8)
    - Methodology and Ethics: Relevance for the Family. pp.1-37. (Box 8)
  - Fern, Richard L.
    - Divine Election, Parental Nurture and Individual Responsibility: Some Reflections on the Puritan Synthesis. pp 1-34. (Box 8)
    - Religious Belief in a Rawlsian Society. The Journal of Religious Ethics, pp. 33-57., n.d. (Box 8)
    - The Rights and Duties of Parents: A Political Proposal. pp. 1-13. (Box 8)
  - Fisher, George Park
  - Fitch, Eleazar
    See Record Group No. 93.
  - Forman, Charles
    See Record Group No. 110.
  - Frei, Hans
    See Record Group No. 76.
  - Goodenough, Erwin R.
    - Articles
      - Catacomb Art. Journal of Biblical Literature, Vol. 81, 1962, pp. 113-142. (Box 10)
      - The Fundamental Motif of Christianity. The Journal of Religion: Vol. XX, No. 1, 1940 Jan, pp. 1-14. (Box 10)
      - Literal Mystery in Hellenistic Judaism. Quantulacumque: 1937 Nov, pp. 227-241. (Box 10)
      - A Neo-Pythagorean Source in Philo Judaeus, Yale Classical Studies III, 1932, pp. 117-164. (Box 10)
      - New Light on Hellenistic Judaism, Journal of Bible and Religion, Vol. V, Part 1, 1937 Mar, pp. 2-12. (Box 10)
      - Philo's Exposition of the Law and His De Vita Mosis, Harvard Theological Review, Vol. XXVII, No. 2, 1933 Apr, pp. 109-125. (Box 10)
      - Symbolism in Hellenistic Jewish Art: The Problem of Method, Journal of Biblical Literature, Vol. LVI, Part II, 1937, pp. 103-114. (Box 10)
    - Book Reviews
      - Belkin, Samuel, Philo and the Oral Law, Journal of Biblical Literature, pp. 413-419. (Box 10)
      - du Mesnil, Comte, Les peintures de la synagogue de DouraEuropas 245-256 apres, Journal of Biblical Literature, pp. 420-423., n.d. (Box 10)
  - Greer, Rowan
    - Alien Citizens: A Marvelous Paradox. pp. 1-27, n.d. (Box 10)
    - Theology and the Church's Experience: Broken Lights. Yale Faculty Discussion, Jan 1975. (Box 10)
  - Gustafson, James M.
    - An Analysis of the Problem of the Role of the Minister. Journal of Religion: 1954, pp. 187-191. (Box 10)
    - A Christian Approach to the Ethics of Abortion. Dublin Review: Winter, 1967/68, pp. 346-364., 1967-1968 (Box 10)
    - Christian Ethics. Religion: 1965, pp. 287-354. (Box 10)
    - Context Versus Principles, A Misplaced Debate in Christian Ethics, Harvard Theological Review 58, no. 2, April 1965. pp. 171-202. (Box 10)
    - The Minister as Moral Counselor. June 20, 1982, pp. 1-14. (Box 10)
    - Moral Discernment in the Christian Life. Virtue, Principles and Rules: pp. 17-36. (Box 10)
    - Patterns of Christian Social Action. Theology Today: July, 1961, pp. 159-171. (Box 10)
    - Religiousity--An Irritating Necessity. Christianity and Crisis: July, 1961, pp. 159-171. (Box 10)
    - Social and theological Interpretation of the Church. Treasure in Earthen Vessels, pp. 99-112. (Box 10)
    - The University as a Community of Moral Discourse. Journal of Religion: October, 1973, 13 pp. (Box 10)
  - Hare, John E.
    - The Apology as an Inverted Parody of Rhetoric. Arethusa, v.14.2, Fall 1981. (Box 12)
    - The Argument from Experience. in Evidence for Faith: Deciding the Question, ed. John Warwick Montgomery. Dallas: Probe Books, 1991, pp.253-273. (Box 12)
    - Aristotelian Justice and the Pull to Consensus. The International Journal of Applied Philosophy, v.3, no.3, Spring 1987, pp.37-49. (Box 12)
    - Aristotle and the Definition of Natural Things. Phronesis, v. 24, 1979, pp. 169-179. (Box 12)
    - The Atonement: How does Christ Bridge the Gap? The Banner, April 13, 1992. (Box 12)
    - Atonement and Incorporation. Perspectives, May 1995. (Box 12)
    - Augustine, Kant, and the Moral Gap. in The Augustinian Tradition, ed. Gareth B. Matthews. Berkeley: University of California Press, 1999, pp.251-262. (Box 12)
    - Christian Scholarship and Human Responsibility. in Christian Scholarship... For What? Grand Rapids: Calvin College, 2003, pp.51-69. (Box 12)
    - Commentary on Timothy J. Brennan, 'Academic Discipline and Representative Advocacy'. Business and Professional Ethics Journal, v.6, no.1, pp.56-62. (Box 12)
    - Commercial Contracts and the Moral Contract: A Response to Nigel Cameron. Christian Scholar's Review, v. 23, no.3, 1994, pp.259-266. (Box 12)
    - Credibility and Bluff. in Nuclear Weapons and the Future of Humanity, ed. Avner Cohen and Steven Lee. Totowa, Rowman and Allanheld, 1986, pp.191-199. (Box 12)
    - Denial of Death. in Caregiving in the Community Hospital: For the Terminally Ill and Bereaved. 1982, pp. 55-62. (Box 12)
    - Eleutheriotes in Aristotle's Ethics. Ancient Philosophy, v. 8, Spring 1988m pp. 19-32. (Box 12)
    - Evolutionary Naturalism and Reducing the Demand of Justice. in Religion in the Liberal Polity, ed. Terence Cuneo. Indiana: University of Notre Dame Press, 2005, pp.74-94. (Box 12)
    - God's Commands and Moral Realism. in The Doctrine of God and Theological Ethics, ed. Alan Torrance and Michael Banner, London: T & T Clark, 2006, pp.55-70. (Box 12)
    - Goodness. in The Cambridge Companion to Christian Philosophical Theology. ed. Charles Taliaferro and Chad Meister, Cambridge: 2010, pp.66-80. (Box 12)
    - The Hospice Movement and the Acceptance of Death. in Hospice U.S.A. New York: Columbia University press, 1983, pp.9-17. (Box 12)
    - Immanuel Kant. in Key Thinkers in Christianity, ed. Adrian Hastings, Alistair Mason and Hugh Pyper. Oxford: 2003. pp.92-97. (Box 12)
    - The Intention to Use Nuclear Weapons. in Evangelicals and the Bishops' Pastoral Letter, ed. Dean C. Curry. Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1984, pp.139-157. (Box 12)
    - Interview with professor John Hare, by David Leimbach. Aporia, v.27, no.1, Spring 2009, pp.16-20. (Box 12)
    - The Invitation. Dialogue, March/April 1995. (Box 12)
    - Is er een Evolutionaire Basis voor de Moraal? Beweging, jaar.69, nr.2, Zomer 2005. (Box 12)
    - Is Moral Goodness without Belief in God Rationally Stable? in Is Goodness without God Good Enough: A Debate on Faith, Secularism, and Ethics, ed. Robert K. Garcia and Nathan L. King. 2009, pp.85-99. (Box 12)
    - Jackie Kennedy and the Seven Dwarfs. Dialogue, v.23, no.6, April/May 1991, pp.20-31. (Box 12)